Nawar Yossef

nawaryossef2@gmail.com 205-826-3790 | Atlanta, GA Nawaryossef.netlify.com

Fullstack JavaScript developer skilled in writing clean, testable code. Experienced with React, Node, vanilla JavaScript, MongoDB, jQuery and mobile-first responsive development with HTML5 and CSS3. Experienced with modern tooling and excited to pick up the right tools for the job

SKILLS

Advanced: JavaScript, React, Redux, Node.js, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, Git, GitHub, NPM, REST APIs. Proficient: MongoDB, Express.js, TDD with Mocha, Chai, Jasmine, Jest, Enzyme, Browserify, ES6.

PROJECTS

SaveMyTrip: save-my-trip.herokuapp.com

- A fullstack app for users to save and email flight information.
- Built with Node.js, MongoDB, JavaScript, Express, jQuery, Mocha.js, Chai.js.

Hot or Cold: game-hot-or-cold.netlify.com

- A front-end app where users attempt to guess a randomly generated number.
- Built with HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Enzyme and Jest.

Grub n Grapes: grub-n-grapes.herokuapp.com

- An app developed with API integration to help users find food and wine venues.
- Built with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Express and jQuery. Uses the Google Maps and Foursquare APIs.

CoderQuiz: coderquiz.herokuapp.com

- A front-end app with multiple guizzes covering topics in HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Built with JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Express

EXPERIENCE

Self-employed | Piano Instructor | Dec 2016 – present

- Provided online piano lessons for a studio of 15+ students.
- Developed lesson plans and maintained a list of diverse students in age and background.
- Engaged students in discussions on music theory and history.

Freelance | Concert Pianist | April 2010 – May 2017

- Performed numerous solo and chamber music recitals.
- Participated in several music festivals in France, United Kingdom, Egypt and North America.
- Performed with a number of orchestras in North America.

The University of Alabama | Graduate Teaching Assistant | Aug 2012 – May 2016

- University pianist and organist.
- Teaching assistant for choral conducting and choir classes.
- Accompanied music students in various chamber settings.
- University Carillon player.
- Piano accompanist for vocal lessons.

EDUCATION

Thinkful | Full Stack Web Development | May 2018 (anticipated)
The University of Alabama | Master of Music | Piano Performance | 2016
Converse College | Master of Music | Piano Performance | 2010